26 chapter 27 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna SU chapter 27 Ruined and Going Downhill As soon as my knees were
sufficiently healed I was turned into a small meadow for a month or two; no other
creature was there; and though I enjoyed the liberty and the sweet grass, yet I
had been so long used to society that I felt very lonely. Ginger and I had become
fast friends, and now I missed her company extremely. I often Ned when I heard
horses' feet passing in the road, but I seldom got an answer; till one morning
the gate was opened, and who should come in but dear old
Ginger. The man slipped off her halter, and left her there. With a joyful Winnie
I trotted up to her; we were both glad to
meet, but I soon found out that it was not for our pleasure that she was
brought to be with me. Her story would be
too long to tell, but the end of it was that she had been ruined by hard riding,
and was now turned off to see what rest would do. Lord George was young and would take
no warning; he was a hard rider, and would hunt whenever he could get the chance,
quite careless of his horse. Soon after I left the stable there
was a steeple chase and he determined to ride. Though the gream told him she was a
little strained, and was not fit for the race, he did not believe it, and on the
day of the race urged Ginger to keep up with the foremost
riders. With her high spirit, she strained herself to the utmost; she came in with
the first three horses, but her wind was touched, besides which he was too heavy
for her, and her back was strained. “And so,” she said, “here we are,
ruined in the prime of our youth and strength, you by a drunkard, and I by a
fool; it is very hard.” We both felt in ourselves that we were not what we had
been. However, that did not spoil the pleasure we had in each other's company;
we did not gallop about as we once did, but we used to feed, and lie down
together, and stand for hours under one of the shady lime trees with our heads
close to each other; and so we passed our time till the family returned from
town. One day we saw the LL come into the meadow, and York was with him. Seeing who
it was, we stood still under our lime tree and let them come up to us. They
examined us carefully. The earl seemed much annoyed. “There is £300 flung away for no
earthly use,” said he; “but what what I care most for is that these horses of my old
friend, who thought they would find a good home with me, are ruined. The mayor
shall have a 12 month's run, and we shall see what that will do for her; but the
black one, he must be sold it is a great pity, but I could not have knees like
these in my stables.” “No, my lord, of course not,” said
York; “but he might get a place where appearances of not much consequence, and
still be well treated. I know a man in Bath, the master of some livery stables,
who often wants a good horse at a low figure; I know he looks well after his
horses. The inquest cleared the horse's character, and your lordship's
recommendation, or mine, would be sufficient warrant for
him.” “You had better write to him, York. I should be more particular about the
place than the money he would fetch.” After this they left
us. “They'll soon take you away,” said Ginger, “and I shall lose the only friend
I have, and most likely we shall never see each other again it is a hard
world!” About a week after this Robert came into the field with a halter, which
he slipped over my head, and led me away.
There was no Leaf taking of Ginger; we Ned to each other as I was led off, and
she trotted anxiously along by the hedge, calling to me as long as she could hear
the sound of my feet. Through the recommendation of York,
I was bought by the master of the livery stables. I had to go by train, which was
new to me, and requ ired a good deal of courage the first time; but as I found
the puffing, rushing, whistling, and, more than all, the trembling of the horsebox
in which I stood did me no real harm, I soon took it
quietly. When I reached the end of my journey I found myself in a tolerably
comfortable stable, and well attended to.
These stables were not so airy and pleasant as those I had been used to. The
stalls were laid on a slope instead of being level, and as my head was kept tied
to the main I was obliged always to stand on the slope, which was very
fatiguing. Men did not seem to know yet that horses can do more work if they can
stand comfortably and can turn about; however, I was well fed and well
cleaned, and, on the whole, I think our master took as much care of us as he
could. He kept a good many horses and carriages of different kinds for
higher Sometimes his own men drove them; at others, the horse and Chase were let
to gentlemen or ladies who drove themselves end of chapter